MEERA SHAH

UX/UI DESIGNER - TORONTO, CA

meera31kanata@gmail.com

www.meerashah.ca

linkedin/in/meera-uxui

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Combined 13 years' experience in advertising and marketing, most recently at Spotify and Google working with the world's top brands to conceptualize, oversee and launch a variety of web products. Transitioning from Ad Sales Account Director into a UX/UI Designer role after updating skills, education and completing several freelance design projects. A deep passion for creative problem-solving and bringing ideas to life. Expert at collaborating with designers & developers and in communicating with key stakeholders.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

User Flows Figma Adobe Photoshop HTML5 React.js

Wireframing Sketch Adobe Illustrator CSS3 & SASS Version Control

Prototyping Adobe Xd Agile Methodology JavaScript Component Architecture

WORK EXPERIENCE

FREELANCE - Designer/Developer, 01/2020 - present Completed Freelance projects as a Designer/Web Developer

- Designed and developed professional portfolio website for Industrial Designer Jason Clerk; Logo & Shopify site for Everyday Ethical Essentials clothing company; and a professional portfolio website for BBC Journalist Dhruti Shah
- Each project included research, defining design needs, mapping user's journeys, wireframing, prototyping and web development

SPOTIFY CANADA - Account Director, Advertising Sales, 02/2015 – 09/2017 Spearheaded partnerships with Fortune 500 brands to execute custom digital products leveraging Spotify's API

- Created 40-60 customized concepts monthly, refined to executable ideas and launched approximately 25-30 custom websites generating ~\$2MM in revenue annually
- Briefed and oversaw designer & development team workflow, providing feedback and approvals on artifacts as "Product Owner" throughout duration of each project

MEERA SHAH

UX/UI DESIGNER - TORONTO, CA

meera31kanata@gmail.com www.meerashah.ca linkedin/in/meera-uxui

- Joined as part of Canadian launch team and scaled the regional office from start-up phase to fully functioning growth market within global organization leading up to IPO
- Collaborated cross-functionally with external Clients, and internally with Data, Research & Insights, Product Marketing and Creative Solutions teams regularly

GOOGLE PLAY MUSIC/SONGZA - Regional Sales Manager, Advertising Sales, 01/2014 – 01/2015 Crafted custom partnerships with Fortune 500 businesses to integrate their brand in to the Songza/Google Play Music platform

- Collaborated with Editorial team to conceptualize and execute ~10-15 branded playlist partnerships annually
- Leveraged user behavioural data to inform and build user flows for advertiser playlist partnerships
- Rare experience working in a start-up, active role in the company's transformation as it was acquired by Google

EXPERTISE

Interaction Design	Data-Driven Solutions	Innovation
User Experience (UX) Strategy	Cross-Function Collaboration	Concept Development
Front-End Web Development	Presentation & Communication	Ideation
Empathy	Storytelling	Attention to Detail

CAREER HIGHLIGHT

2016 Media Innovation Award Shortlist – Best in Consumer Engagement

McDonald's, OMD & Spotify for the McDonald's Road Trip Playlist Website

EDUCATION

User Interface Design Certificate Brainstation, 06/2019 Web Development Diploma Brainstation, 12/2018 Bachelor of Design (B. Des.) O.C.A.D., 05/2005